[Music]
[Applause]
I offer my
BS to the Divine in you
[Applause]
generally
speaking everybody wants
something either in their
life or from their
[Applause]
life if I ask
you what do you
want do you know the answer to that
question do you want wealth
do you want name
Fame do you want
success do you want
peace do you want
happiness do you want
Pleasures or do you want all of the
above
if
you know what you
want life can
be
easy you
can live if you know what you
want if you don't know what you
want chances
are you are just getting by
[Applause]
chances are you're not
leaving but you're just getting
[Applause]
by imagine you walk into a
uh
Supermarket you have the money with
you and you even have the list of things
you want to buy
[Applause]
your life becomes easy all you have to
do
is go around the aisles and pick up the
items and then check
out but imagine you walk into the
same
shop and you don't know what you
[Applause]
want if you don't know what you want
then how are you actually going to make
any choices at
all if you don't know what you
want you are relying on the suggestions
given to you by other
[Applause]
people imagine a uh
worker in the
store sees that you have been walking
around
for couple of
hours and that you have not bought
anything he or she may just come to you
and say can I help you with
something if you have even any vague
idea of what you
want the person may be able to help
you if you don't have any idea
the
person in spite of all their wanting may
not be able to help
[Applause]
you it all is still very
manageable but imagine you walk into a
store in a different
country and you don't know the language
at all
let's assume you know
English and you walk into a store in
China and you don't
have even the most basic
Chinese
knowledge can that person the shopkeeper
or the stone own
owner do you think they can still help
you first the problem is you don't
know what you want and second now the
problem is you don't speak the same
language
either bit
trouble and third imagine if the person
at the other end is not even a good
salesperson you are done for the
day that person's not going to offer you
any choices
because he or she doesn't care whether
you buy or you don't
buy and even if they did they can't
speak the same
[Applause]
language
so what is my
point my point is this is how nature
operates to those who know what they
[Applause]
want nature can help a great
deal if you
know their
language by that I mean if you know the
language of the
nature nature can help you a great
[Applause]
deal it can direct you it can chart a
course for you it can instill the right
ingredients in you to get to success to
to get to what you
want but if you don't know what you want
how can nature give you anything
then and if you don't know what you want
anything you get from
nature you will need to be happy with
that why because you have no basis to
complain if I walk into a restaurant and
I sit down on my table and I say you
know give me anything for
breakfast and the
uh the waiter brings me very yummy
strawberry
[Applause]
pancakes with maple syrup and vanilla
ice
cream and some freshly cut
fruits top with
strawberries and I tell that person
oh this is good but I actually wanted
something
safery now do you think I have the basis
to
complain do you think I have the reason
complain either I should
have specified my order at the first
place at the beginning that I'm looking
for something Savory so okay bring me
hash
browns if not
I should be happy with just about
anything I I
get I don't know if you
can absorb the
message at this point in time but it is
something for you to think
about nature is happy to serve
[Applause]
you it is also even happy to listen to
your requirements and serve you
according to what you want
only if you
specify only if you're clear
[Applause]
enough let's RND the tape for a
moment let's go back into the same
restaurant it's morning
time the waiter comes to
you and he
says what would you like for breakfast
today and you say oh I would love
some brown bread hash brown and a cup of
coffee the waiter goes inside to place
the order for you to have it
prepared a few minutes
later you call the waiter again and you
say oh you know what I actually changed
my mind can you please cancel that order
and uh bring
me pancakes
the waiter may be kind enough to tell
you sure no problems we can do that for
you the wer goes
in tells the
person the the person in the kitchen
okay there's a change in the order so
don't make what you were making earlier
and instead make these Banana
Pancakes no
problem a few minutes go
by and you call the waiter
again and you tell the
[Music]
waiter oh you know I'm really sorry to
disturb you and I'm really sorry to be a
pain but can you please change my order
one last
time please can you just give me fruit
yogurt and with French
toast the waiter might give you a blank
look or an angry
look or he may tell you look I have to
check I have to go inside and check if
your order is already prepared you
know but it's okay I I'll you know
manage he goes
in and he sees that your coffee is
already
ready but now you want food yogurt and
French toast
[Applause]
and
uh
anyway with some
grief your order may be
prepared and they bring you your coffee
your food yogurt your French toast of
course now you tell them that you don't
want coffee because you're having yogurt
so instead you may go for orange
[Applause]
juice you can almost be certain to see a
frown on his
face and maybe even
disagreement
nevertheless he's got a job to do he's
kind so he brings you your orangee
[Applause]
juice once a while or once in your
lifetime this may be
okay but imagine doing it every day
imagine doing it every time you go
[Applause]
there you do the math you tell me what
is the likelihood that next time you
will be taken
[Applause]
seriously and the same goes with god
with nature whatever name you want to
give with
[Applause]
Providence they are there to give
you God is there to help you nature is
there to serve you but if you're going
to keep changing the
order you're going to have
problems and if you're going to
keep changing your
mind nature one day is going to stop
taking you
seriously they say oh this person always
does
that you go there you say oh you know
can I coffee in the beginning and then
you change your mind or can I have
coffee at
last sorry like orange juice orange
juice first oh no actually I want hash
brown
first they're going to top stop taking
you seriously because they no longer
care about you they're happy to lose
this indecisive
customer so if you are indecisive nature
is happy to lose
[Applause]
you but secondly
if you are
also inor
unorganized which means you keep
changing your priorities first time you
want orange juice then you change your
mind you want coffee first then you want
hash browns and you want pancakes you
want yogurt you want everything
basically but you don't know what you
want red flags
up if that is your case if you are that
person
you need to sit down first you need to
do some
thinking and you need to specify your
order and you need to tell yourself no
matter what I'm sticking to my
order I may throw up I may puke right
here on the table but I'm going to eat
what I've
ordered and that's the key to
remember that nature wants to give you
but you need to know what you want
now if I walk into a
restaurant and it's a very busy
restaurant I waited 20 minutes to get my
table I walk in
there and I say
uh you know I'd like B I like pancakes
hash browns coffee orange juice fruit
yogurt fruit salads and like some uh
freshly cracked you know
fruits and i' like uh uh tea as well
lemon
tea and uh I would like a Dosa and I'd
like some North Indian stuff and please
bring it to me all at
once they may have troubles doing that
if they're very
busy not only that if you tell them
bring it to me all in one go and bring
it to me right away
it's not possible is
it and if even if you do get it all in
one
go and by sheer stint of luck you do get
it all at once can you eat all of that
in one shot
no so what am I getting
at nature is very
busy nature is never idle
nature is always working Nature has a
job to
do if you look at flowing water it is
always flowing if you look at Sun it is
coming out setting in day in day
out the Four
Seasons they emerging when due the
rains the
clouds everything agriculture
everything so nature is very BAS
but it is also very
Adept and and and and
um and willing to serve you only if you
can specify what do you
want but nature nature cannot give you
everything that you want your God cannot
give you everything that you want at the
time you want you have to be
patient you put a seed in the
ground and you
wait and you irrigate and you offer it
whatever water is required and other
nutrients and you have to
wait there's a saying you know they use
very frequently in Australia you know I
mean that's where the place where I
first heard it and you cannot make nine
ladies pregnant and deliver the baby in
a
month you've got to wait
[Applause]
so you have to
prioritize and you have to be
specific and you need to be
patient and you need to stay
[Applause]
Co imagine I
uh walk into the restaurant say you know
I would like
these I like to have some Kish I would
like this pan pasta and I'd like this
Yaki and I would love some
bread and
butter when you place the order and you
walk
out you leave your
table and you leave no sign behind that
you intend to come
back what are the chances that your
order is going to be
served how are they to know that you are
going to even come back and how are they
to believe you
so once you've placed the order you've
got to be there to take it to enjoy
it a lot of people want to move
on imagine you start digging a well
because you want
water you go down 10 ft and you're tired
you say you know probably there's no
water in this land and you go to another
place and dig another 10 ft you go to
another place and dig another 10 ft
and Another Place Another 10 ft and you
keep doing
it you can do it all your life but
you're not going to get water if you
want water from the ground you have to
sit at one place keep
digging of course you need to be smart
about selection of the place at the
first
place but you need to keep
digging once you go down 60 ft 80 ft 90
ft chances are you're going to get
water from the ground
[Applause]
and that's what you have to keep in
mind with nature once you have released
a thought in the
cosmos that I would like
this if that is the only thing you want
you will have
that not in your time frame in Nature's
time
frame if you want other things as well
you have
diluted
your your diluted the
strength the
concentration of your
thought and then if you keep shifting
and keep juggling what do I want more
than the
other
then you basically are either not going
to get any of those or you're you are
going to get those in proportions purely
[Applause]
usable so you need to decide whether you
want family first or do you want
success do you want happiness first or
do you want joy do you want Pleasures do
you want health or do you want
fame or do you want the label a degree a
promotion is it wrong to want all these
things in one go actually it
is but it is not wrong to aim for all
these things and that's a
difference you can aim for all these
things but you need to
prioritize and you need to it's you know
first in first
out the goal that is your first goal you
will achieve it
first imagine you on a on a block of
lands
and you want to
construct certain buildings on this land
or certain
artifacts now I want all of those but
clearly I have to go sequentially one
after the
other maybe if I'm really
loaded I could do multiple in one go but
the fact is still there is a by the very
nature they are
sequential I cannot sit here close my
eyes and I may have have a million
dollar sitting right here but that that
does not mean that I'm going to have
everything I want within a
minute having resources is one thing but
having patience is really what's
required so you really need to be
patient and prioritize and know what you
want if you ask me what should you want
it's a question I've been asked many
times people come and ask me
me what should be our life's
[Applause]
goal you know I'm
somewhat
amused and
dismayed at their question how can I
tell you what should be your life's goal
it is your
life and if I give you a goal that means
I have just conditioned your mind and
I'm so against conditioning the mind the
whole point is to remove the
conditioning of the Mind
so you need to set your own goal you
need to count on your experience you
need to see what gives you Joy what
gives you satisfaction what helps you do
the right
Karma what helps
you help
others and then select a goal
accordingly all I can tell you is your
goal should not be a purely selfish goal
your goal should have little bit of
stuff for you some for those who care
about you and uh some for those who are
part of the same world where you live
in you have a duty of care to all
those so you need to delve deep in
you and within you to one know what you
should be
doing and to know what you ought to be
doing
and to know what can you
do and to
prioritize set
yourself a reasonable time
frame but don't don't go mad on its non-
achievements you can choose to either
leave a balanced
life which means you may say I'm going
to spend every week no matter what 10
hours with my family or 20 hours or X
hours and I'm going to give for my body
another 4 to 6 hours every week I'm
going to go work
out and I'm going to give another 4
hours for meditation every
week and I'm going to give 50 hours to
my work or 40 hours or 30 hours or 20
hours you decide that
number but it is important to stick to
that number
all my meetings with a lot of
people I never heard anybody tell me
that they want
God why I don't know should they want
God I don't
[Applause]
know but when you want
something as pure and as Divine as
God you can only have him if when that
is the only thing when he is the only
one you want
and that actually not only goes true for
God but for
everything when the only thing that
matters to you in your life the one you
want when you are willing to give up
everything for that one thing that
matters to
you you can be almost certain to have
that one
thing it may take some
time it may take longer than you
anticipate
or you anticipate it at the first
place but you can be almost certain it's
going to
[Applause]
come so if I say I want to build a
company as big as I don't know let's say
Microsoft that is a rubbish goal believe
me you can aim to be the industry
leader you can aim to be creative you
can aim to have your own business you
can aim to have a large business you can
aim to have a better quality product
than your
competitor but if your goal is to have a
bigger company than somebody else is
having then the only way you can do it
is to go back in time and start it when
the other person started it with the
same market
conditions am I saying you should not
aim big no I'm saying you can aim for
Moon if you so
wished but you need to have your own
goal not a goal that is determined
by somebody
else not a goal that is determined based
on something else have your own goal do
you think having a company bigger than
Microsoft is going to give you
Joy or having a company that is
profitable is going to give you Joy or
having a company having a product that
people are using is that going to give
you
Joy often people set their goals not
based on their
own wanting from within but based on
what they observe
outside and that is a load of rubbish if
you ask
me if you if the only thing you want in
life is
to
have a company bigger than somebody
else's chances are you're not going to
get there
ever but if you that could be your dream
but if your goal is I want to build
something I don't care about the
size but I care about the quality I care
about my product I care about my
offering then
everything else is going to start to
fall in
[Applause]
place you may disagree but I think
Destiny has a role to play in your
[Applause]
life
and when you stay course it makes sure
that you that it takes you to the right
place at the right
time and when you're at the right place
at the right time and doing the right
thing in the right time
frame at the right speed with the right
mindset the right
outcome automatically
manifests before
[Applause]
you and so much so for
Destiny when you want peace
within and I think that is a noble goal
to have if you ask me
what should you want I would say one of
the things should be
peace because you can only be peaceful
if you're
contented when your head is in the right
spot you can only be
peaceful the struggle that is
unnecessary leaves
you so be practical set your
goals work towards it and prior
them if you're 30 or 25 or 40 I don't
know you may say I'm going to give the
next 4 years to my
work if you are 45 or or depending on
your own personal circumstances
regardless of what your age
is you may say my family is more
important to me than my work if that is
a choice you make then don't win if you
don't get promotions at work and because
you're not working 60 hours or because
your mind is not in the right
place or because you don't have the
right qualifications don't complain it's
Choice you're making you are saying I
want my family over and above my
work that's a
choice so you prioritize don't say I
want family and I want
work you can't eat the cake and have it
too unless you can make your own door
and make another cake at home that is
possible and for that to
happen you need to have razor sharp
Focus if you have Supreme
concentration and you have
uh excellent ability to switch
off you can have
both if you can be fully at work when at
work and be fully at home when at home
you can have both family and work
if you want to work 80 hours a
week and you want to spend 10 hours at
the gym and you want to Merit head for 4
hours and you want to spend 20 hours
with the family and you would also like
decent sleep of about 6 to 8 hours every
day every
night I don't think it's going to happen
do
you do you even have those many hours in
the
day so
be
pragmatic think about what you
want the more you
want the weaker the
thought the more you add to it the
feeble it becomes the more feeble it
[Applause]
becomes and that's something you need to
remember want okay fine have a list okay
fine
if you know what you want and you
know the order you want then leave the
rest to
Nature it will do the work for you
you'll be
[Applause]
amazed but remember to be
patient Rome was not built in a day they
say so once you have released the
thought into the cosmos about what you
want
keep working at it with a calm mind with
a cool head adopting and adapting all
that you need to along the way to turn
it into a
success and you will be
greeted by success before
long that is what I experienced in my
own
life both on material and spiritual
fronts
your experiences experiences may be
different but for me and for many others
with whom I shared this philosophy it
worked for
them
whether it's going to work for you that
depends on your tenacity that depends on
your
determination that depends how firmly
you take it up and it depends how
clear you are but what you want it all
depends on these
[Applause]
things so know what you
want and the nature will help you get
there if you don't know what you
want either don't complain when you get
anything that you
get
or be happy with whatever you
get because when you don't specify what
you want
you are out there in the open
market and may go for just about any
price Del deep turn inward discover
yourselves ask yourself some fundamental
questions about how do you want to be
living your
life and what would you really want in
your
life think about it that's all I have
for you
[Applause]
today om
Krishna Krishna Hur hurry hry
H H Hur
H H Om
[Applause]